Conan O'Brien needs a fan.
Wanna talk to Conan?
Visit teamcoco.com slash call Conan.
Okay, let's get started.
Please.
Yes.
Hey.
Hi, Tom, welcome to Conan O'Brien.
Hello.
He needs a fan, nice sweater.
Wow. Thank you.
Good job.
First of all, Gourley on just being so positive so quickly.
Tom, so nice to see you.
I see you have your-
You too.
Your Christmas tree in the background.
It looks dark where you are.
We're in Los Angeles, where are you?
I'm Conan from Dublin, Ireland.
Oh, you're in Dublin.
Look at that fine Irish cable knit
fisherman sweater and Christmas tree.
I didn't live in the light.
I just wanna trade places with you.
I'm sorry, Mr. Gourley is making this sound
like the home shopping network.
Tom here is wearing a fine cable net sweater.
It's gorgeous.
It's made of a fine Dublin weave.
Sir, tell us, and Tom, what's your last name?
Lawler.
Okay, Tom Lawler, calling from or calling,
I guess zooming in, calling, whatever you wanna say.
Appearing to us magically from Dublin.
I love Dublin.
I love the few times I've visited there.
I've had a fantastic time.
Yeah, you've been a few times.
I've been a few times.
One of the times I went, I met up with a bunch of other,
well, very famous Irish comedians from Ireland
who were all hilarious, and we all did a show together
at the Ambassador's residence in Phoenix Park,
and I thought these are the funniest people I've ever met,
and then all of us got into a cab
to go into Dublin to get a drink,
and the cabbie was funnier than all of us,
and I thought that's Dublin.
There's just everyone that's just super high
professional level funny.
So no pressure on me then for the rest of this interview.
Well done.
Well, we can always say later on that you're,
you know, you're going through a depressive period,
you know, and so that gets you off the hook.
Tom, tell me a little bit about yourself.
Well, so I live in Dublin, as you know,
and I right now am the co-director of a festival
here in Dublin that the city started a number of years ago
called Bram Stoker Festival,
which is basically a way of us celebrating
the life and legacy and work of Bram Stoker,
who wrote Dracula.
Yep, and so this is interesting to me
because I don't have to say, I admit,
I don't know much about Bram Stoker, obviously.
His work is very famous,
but I don't know much about the man himself.
Was he Irish?
Yeah, he was Irish, and I think part of that,
one of the big reasons the festival was started
was I guess to kind of reclaim him as an Irish author, right?
So everybody knows Joyce and Beckett as Irish authors,
but I think a lot of people had kind of assumed
or thought that Bram Stoker was British,
and the Brits have a long history of claiming Irish people
as their own when they become very successful,
so it was kind of a way of taking it back
and kind of reclaiming him as a Dublin-born Irish writer, yeah.
That's actually very, I mean, that's fascinating to me.
You may have heard me say, I've said it many times,
because it's kind of fascinating slash sad to me,
but my people emigrated from Ireland
in the late 19th century,
and we've been living in central Massachusetts,
and I'm still genetically 100% Irish,
which is I think tragic.
Tom, will you please reclaim him?
Yeah.
Wait.
And Americans desperately want me to be reclaimed,
and they mean taken back to Ireland and kept there.
Well, we'd be delighted to reclaim you
and have you at the festival anytime, or in Dublin.
I mean, you're hugely popular.
I feel like lots of the friends or the fans
on this podcast are coming from Ireland as well, right?
You've got to go there.
No, it's funny, we do have,
I do get recognition from Irish people for the TV show,
but also a lot from the podcast, which is very nice.
So I'd love to go back there,
and I'd love to reconnect,
because I think it would be lovely.
That's a word that I hear a lot.
Lovely.
I've heard that in Ireland, they say,
isn't that lovely?
Also, they say, correct me if I'm wrong, Tom,
in America, people say um.
So if you ask me a question, I say, um, yeah.
I live near the Volkswagen dealership,
but about two blocks away.
The people I've met in Dublin say M, E, M.
Yeah, Gretan Norton.
Yeah, have you noticed that?
Yeah, actually, yeah, it's funny you say that,
because um.
M. M.
It just happened.
M.
When I moved to the States for college,
and I remember that was one of the first things
people pointed out when I lived there.
I went to college in Pennsylvania,
and one of the first things people noticed was,
why do you say M all the time?
We don't realize it, but yeah,
but that's one of the differences we have, I guess.
When I was in New York, I had a therapist,
a very brilliant woman who was from Dublin,
and she used to, I'd tell her about
whatever was going on in my life, and she'd say,
M, I think you're crazy.
You know.
That was her official diagnosis.
Her official diagnosis was that my family was shite,
and that I'm crazy.
So this is interesting, so you're trying to,
is there anyone else who we don't know is really Irish,
or can we start claiming people who aren't Irish,
but just claim them anyway, you know?
Like Daniel Craig, let's just start saying,
did you know he's from Dublin, even though he's not?
We should start grabbing cool people and saying they're Irish.
Absolutely, I mean, look, if you've got a list of people
you want me to start claiming as Irish,
we can put a festival together about all of them,
if the need to be, that's fine.
Yeah, Messi, Messi's from Dublin.
Lionel Messi's a true son of Ireland,
and then he was stolen!
He was stolen and taken away to Argentina.
We should just, because there are no better liars
in the world and confabulous than the Irish,
so we should just start making a list.
Batman, Batman's from, Uncle Sam!
Famous, the Irish.
No one thinks of Uncle Sam anymore.
What are you talking, no one thought of Uncle Sam
since like 1911.
I was trying to think of the most American icon possible.
No, no, no, I mean like Beyonce,
did you know that she's from Dublin?
Did you know that she's from Galway?
Yeah, it's Beyonce McNoles.
Yeah.
Wow.
I'm telling you, I think, Tom,
I think we're really onto something.
Sure, Bram Stoker, let's do that,
but I think you're missing a real opportunity here,
and I will help you generate the list.
We're gonna come up with just all of the coolest people.
And Keanu Reeves.
Keanu Reeves is from the...
Ha ha ha ha ha ha.
He's from the South Country down there.
He's from Cork.
I don't know, we could, who's to stop us?
No one can stop us.
I mean, there's no one on this side who's gonna stop you.
I think if you guys have a list, you know,
put together whatever list and we'll find some,
I mean, there's so many people that come to Ireland
and then realize that they've got Irish heritage, right?
Like Obama was here a few years ago
and he's got a very strong, like Irish...
You can't have him.
I mean, there's so many, you go for it.
Okay, all right, you guys can keep him then.
Yeah, we need to keep him.
I know.
Wait, can we trade if you're getting Beyonce and stuff?
No. No?
Okay.
We can't trade?
Can't trade.
Depending on who you were, sorry,
depending on who you were gonna say, maybe, yeah.
It's gonna be all worked out.
Listen, Tom, you and I are gonna work this out.
We're gonna start an exchange,
but we're gonna make lists of people
that the Irish can claim
and then I think we should get to have Liam Neeson.
Yes.
You know, he's so cool.
I'm just curious, how many of you would we have to trade
to get one Liam Neeson?
You know what, I looked it up, 35 Conans.
Yes.
35 Conans gets you Liam Neeson's shoulder.
Worth it.
I'll take it.
Sold.
You don't think these celebrities would have a problem
with these festivals?
Do as they're told.
Okay.
I would love for you to say that to Beyonce.
Well, I'm not gonna say that to Beyonce,
but boy, I'm gonna say it to Liam Neeson.
I don't fear him at all.
Confusion.
Yeah, he's my height and looks like,
I talked to him not long ago
and it was so clear to me the minute he walked in the room,
like, oh, that's a real man.
I'm a Lucky Charms leprechaun.
Anyway, Tom, this sounds like a good endeavor.
I'm glad that you're working on building up,
reclaiming what rightfully belongs to Ireland.
I think that's important.
Yeah, I mean, we try to, you know,
there's only so much you can get out of Dracula, right?
In terms of a festival, like we need new ideas every year
and we try to present it in different ways.
So we have a lot of fun with it.
It's not just all, we don't just, you know,
we describe it as we're not just like, muahaha.
Like we try to have a lot of fun with it
and kind of bring- Although that sounds fun.
Yeah, that sounds really fun.
I would go to a muahaha fest.
Come to muahaha.
Well, also I'm not aware of what else did Bram Stoker,
I don't really know, other than, I know him for Dracula,
but did he write, you know, erotic fiction that I could read?
And if it's not erotic fiction, I don't want to read it.
The first book he ever wrote was actually a book,
like it was a guide for civil servants,
like people who were like, oh, I'm turned on.
So he did write some erotic fiction.
Exactly.
So depending on your case, I guess, that's a good one.
But none of his other work has really made it into the kind of consciousness
and the same way that Dracula has.
But I mean, you know, I don't think like being a one hit wonder for Dracula,
I feel like it's still a pretty good-
Oh, yeah.
Rear highlight. Yeah.
So we tried to kind of stretch out everything.
I mean, some of the stuff that I really enjoy,
like we've done a lot of research into Bram
and there's some great kind of lesser known things about him.
Like he once tried to save a man that was drowning in the Thames in London
because he didn't live in the UK for a while.
See, that's why they got to claim him.
That's the problem.
Yeah.
If you even, if an Irish person goes and lives in London for a week,
they get to put up a blue plaque somewhere and say, yep,
he's the UK's own Bram Stoker.
You know, it's just not fair.
Only if they're wildly successful though.
I mean, if they're, you know, as soon as something goes wrong,
then they're immediately Irish, according to the British again.
Oh, okay. All right.
They just, those plaques, by the way, are put up with Velcro.
They come off the minute you do something.
And everyone's getting canceled these days.
I think those plaques probably come off as quickly as they go on.
So I'm going to bring my own blue plaque the next time I go to London
and some super glue and just glue it onto a building.
That's good.
And say, you know, sir Conan O'Brien lived here
or stood here and chewed some bubble yum for 10 minutes.
You're giving yourself a knighthood.
Sure, why not?
Okay.
Yeah.
I want to go back to Ireland,
but you're going to have a knighthood from Britain?
Sure.
So what color plaque do they use in Ireland?
If I go to Ireland, I want to glue some plaques up.
I'm pretty sure we use blue plaques as well.
You use blue plaques too?
Yeah, I'm pretty sure.
All right.
We'll find out because I want to find out
exactly what they look like.
Make this priority.
Excuse me, Toms.
Oh, Toms got such a busy schedule
working on the Bram Stoker Festival.
Yeah, you've got 11 months of downtime.
Yeah, yeah.
You know, how many plastic fangs can you buy?
Yeah, I've got some time to put in.
You've got a pretty easy move ahead.
I am a civil servant.
I'm here to clean up the bureaucracy.
You can do that.
["The Stoker Festival"]
Tom, I'm going to come to Dublin and glue some plaques up.
That's what I'm going to do.
I want some plaques up that say,
Conan stood here, Conan bought some stew here,
Conan was asked to leave this gap
for unfolding too many sweaters, but not buying one.
Things like that.
Well, and how's your life going, Tom?
How's everything in life?
Yeah, it's pretty good.
I mean, as you said, I've got a few easier months ahead
because we're just in planning now,
but outside of work, things are going.
Yeah, things are good.
I'm looking forward to Christmas.
You got your tree up.
Have you done your shopping?
Got my tree up here.
I just started doing some shopping yesterday.
Yeah, things are, yeah.
I would think that Dublin would be a wonderful Christmas town.
It would feel very Christmassy there.
Yeah, it does, but it has that horrible thing
of kind of in the winter time here
when it's freezing outside
and it's roasting inside every shop you go into.
So you kind of panic buy really quickly
everything that you don't need
for far more than you would typically spend
because you're too warm and it's all very stressful.
But yeah, I mean, it is, aside from that,
it's a really nice place to be,
although it's a very specific complaint.
Yeah, that's just, you have
such a specific complaint.
The temperature difference between the outdoors
and the shop itself is such that I buy more quickly.
I can't live anymore.
I must take my own life.
Tom, do you have a question for Conan at all?
Yeah, actually, I mean, so, you know,
we're in the stage now of kind of festival planning
where we're thinking of ideas for next year.
And I guess just, you know,
I run the festival with my friend Maria
and we're collaborators.
We collaborate with each other and with artists.
And we wondered whether you have ideas for events
that we could run at the festival next year,
or if you yourself would like to come to the festival
and put on a show.
Oh, wow.
Well, first of all, I always,
I take any excuse to, you know, get in front of a crowd.
I'm very sick that way.
So, you know, it all depends on-
It would almost guarantee you one of those plaques as well,
I could say.
I would like a special edition red plaque.
Listen, Tom.
Say no more.
No, Tom, I bring my own plaques.
I don't want anything factual on my plaques.
I want all kinds of crazy information.
So it all depends on the schedule,
but obviously I'd love to attend a Bram Stoker festival.
In terms of ideas for what works,
I think you have to embrace the Dracula of it all.
I think trying to downplay Dracula is a mistake.
You've got to lean into Dracula.
And that means contests, find the Dracula.
He's somewhere in Dublin.
And, you know, you have, I mean, don't you think?
Absolutely. Whatever.
Have some fun.
Yeah. And then, you know the way there's a,
we have here in the United States, a chili eating contest,
and we have hot dog eating contest.
How many hot dogs can people eat very quickly?
I think it would be, how much blood can you drink
from this carotid artery?
Who can drink it the fastest?
Obviously you don't drink it from a real person,
but you simulate a carotid artery.
And then you have a whole bunch of people
like in a pie eating contest and see who can down the most.
And it's not real blood.
There's like fake cadavers on a table.
Dummies, like crash test dummies.
And who can drink the most blood?
And it's one, two, three, go.
And you know, the blood can be,
I mean, I would prefer it if it was real human blood,
but I understand how that's going to turn some people off.
But we could come up with a caro syrup or something.
Actually a great idea.
I think it's a fantastic-
You have to, like a blood drinking contest
and also like intestines, but they're linked sausages
that you have to just keep eating like a hot dog contest.
Well, that's a werewolf.
What are you talking about?
Dracula, hold it.
Dracula doesn't eat your intestines.
You know what? You're right.
They don't eat it.
What are you talking about?
I love how you immediately got angry.
Like, what are you talking about?
And I said Dracula, and you went, oh, right.
No, he drinks your blood.
Is that a werewolf though?
Yeah, a werewolf will disembowels you, rips you up,
tosses your innards all around,
and then goes running over the hill going, ah, woo.
You're right, and I'd like to formally apologize.
To the Bram Stoker community.
To the Bram Stoker estate,
I'd like to have my plaques taken down.
I'm sorry.
Hey, is there a Bram Stoker estate,
meaning are there people that still profit
from Dracula movies and things like that?
There is, yeah, actually the Bram Stoker estate
kind of allow us to continue with the festival every year.
He has a great grand nephew called Dacre Stoker,
who comes to the festival quite often,
who's also an author and has actually written
extensively about Dracula,
but also wrote a prequel book to Dracula.
Can I ask you something?
Which is soon to be made into a film.
Does his great-grandson ever appear to be someone
who's lived for millennia?
You know, like is like hundreds of years old
and actually could be Bram Stoker,
and does he ever say, well, when I wrote Dracula,
er, er, I mean, when my great-great,
em, em, when my great-grandfather wrote it,
and then you realize that he is in fact Vlad Dracul.
He does have a very particular look,
so you might be onto something there.
I'm telling you, lean into Dracula,
because the civil service novel ain't going nowhere fast.
Melville wrote one of those, Bartleby the Scrivener,
and it didn't sell, and then he went back to the giant fish,
and again, he was in the money.
So you gotta lean into what works.
And I think if Bram were alive today,
he'd be writing all kinds of more Dracula.
You know, Dracula goes to Las Vegas,
he'd be doing rom-coms with Dracula,
Dracula has a Nancy Meyers kitchen.
You know, there'd be all kinds of,
Dracula would be in the Marvel universe.
Oh.
I mean, he would, he just would.
So, lean into it, I say.
Hey, speaking of eating people's intestines,
I hear you're quite a cook, is that right?
Good transition, by the way.
Yeah, thank you, thank you.
I was told to get that in.
Yes, you're a cook, is that right?
So I'm not, I mean, I'm not a professional cook,
but it is the thing that I love doing the most, yeah.
And as I've got, you know,
I enjoy cooking for like big groups of people,
but I actually just started seeing someone recently enough
who is also a really good cook.
And I think he is in fact, far better than I am.
Which is-
That threatens your identity, doesn't it?
Slightly, yeah.
Because you thought of yourself as the great cook,
and now this other person comes along
and he's the better cook.
Can I come to your house?
Can you cook for me?
Sure, yeah.
We can both cook for you,
and then maybe you could decide which one is better.
Okay, all right.
I don't know that you have the most refined palate.
I don't have any palate.
I have a terrible, you know, I'll eat anything.
Her meter is Burger King or not Burger King.
That's the only thing that she can determine.
I, well that's, and you know,
I think Ireland used to get a bad rap
for not having very good food.
And that may have been true for a long time,
but I feel like in the 1990s,
that reputation started to change greatly
because what I heard is that young, brilliant chefs
that couldn't get a job in London would go to Dublin,
and suddenly that became this center of great cuisine.
And I think that's emanated out now
that people in Ireland actually enjoy very good food.
Is that true?
Totally, yeah.
Ireland's a great place to eat.
I think even, you know, a few years ago,
it might have just been in Dublin,
but now across the country,
there's so many incredible places to eat.
And I think, yeah, we had a bad reputation for, you know,
like ham and cabbage is like what people think, you know,
is like, although ham and cabbage is a pretty good meal,
if you ask me, but it was kind of what people expected
Irish food to be, but now it's much broader than that.
Well, I think I grew up, my mother exclusively,
there was a lot of fried ham,
a lot of ham and then fried ham and potato,
and potato with fried ham and then fried ham with potato.
It was delicious, it was really good,
but it was a lot of that.
And I think that was handed down generationally
because when her people left Ireland, that's what it was.
And so even all those years later in the 1970s,
I'm eating a ton of fried ham
to the point where I think I died two years ago
with a massive heart attack.
You're Dracula.
I'm Dracula.
Hey, wait a minute, back me up on this, Tom.
In Stoker's Dracula, doesn't he also turn into a wolf,
a werewolf on the Demeter?
Have you read Dracula?
You're really cutting me out here.
I would love it, he's just going on and on about it.
We're reclaiming Bram Stoker.
I'm reclaiming Bram Stoker.
I just realized he's a wolf,
he could turn into a wolf, a bat, and a mist.
Are you gonna fight me on the,
everyone knows Dracula eats intestines?
Yeah, you really want the sausage thing to happen.
Cause that's just stupid.
If you won it all, it'd be on the weirdest technicality.
I'll take it, I'll take it.
We all know Dracula urinated places to mark them
and he was always chasing cats.
What are you talking about?
He could turn into a wolf.
Okay.
I'm sorry, it's true, right?
You can, yeah.
Okay, so.
Yeah, all right, so we'll have-
Syndicated in the most major way.
Yeah, all right, well Tom,
I guess that's another suggestion
for your Bram Stoker festival is-
Some werewolf events.
Well, not werewolf, Dracula turning into a dog.
It's not a werewolf.
Eating sausages.
It's a werewolf.
Yeah, he could also turn into the thing
from the Fantastic Four.
Okay, now you're just poking fun and that's ridiculous.
Well, I'm really happy with myself.
Tom, thank you.
Thank you for reaching out.
Thank you.
Speaking to us, I will take it to heart
this whole Bram Stoker controversy.
I will work in the fact that Bram Stoker is Irish
in every conversation that I can in the most awkward way.
And I will fight this-
Thank you, I'd really appreciate it.
All right, well, happy holidays.
Yeah, you too.
And thank you so much.
Take care.
Thank you guys, thanks very much.
Thank you. Bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Conan O'Brien needs a friend.
With Conan O'Brien, Sonam Ovsessian, and Matt Gourley.
Produced by me, Matt Gourley.
Executive produced by Adam Sachs, Nick Leal,
and Jeff Ross at Team Coco,
and Colin Anderson and Cody Fisher at Earwolf.
Theme song by The White Stripes.
Incidental music by Jimmy Vivino.
Take it away, Jimmy.
Our supervising producer is Aaron Blair,
and our associate talent producer is Jennifer Samples.
Engineering by Eduardo Perez.
Additional production support by Mars Melnick.
Talent booking by Paula Davis, Gina Battista, and Brit Kahn.
You can rate and review this show on Apple Podcasts,
and you might find your review read on a future episode.
Got a question for Conan?
Call the Team Coco hotline at 669-587-2847
and leave a message.
It too could be featured on a future episode.
And if you haven't already,
please subscribe to Conan O'Brien Needs a Friend
wherever fine podcasts are downloaded.
This has been a Team Coco production
in association with Earwolf.